Hey there, Cowboys Nation. Kyleman's
here with the newest Dallas Cowboy,
Malachi Lawrence from UCF, the edge
rusher. Excited to have you here in
Dallas. It's already It already looks
great with the the star on the hat uh
that you're wearing now. What have the
last 24 hours been like for you getting
to this point and now uh on your way to
the star in Frisco?
>> Right. Um these last 24 hours have been
crazy but a blessing to say like all
glory to God. Um I wouldn't be here
without him. But just celebrating with
family, hearing my name called, dream
come true. So I've been playing football
since I was five. So always dreamed of
this moment.
>> Was it a surprise to to hear your name
called by Dallas in the first round or
is this something that you kind of
thought was in the works?
>> Right. Uh I say in between like I kind
of thought it was in the works, but it
also surprised me cuz like I I did not
know like where I was going to get
drafted at all. But I did have like a
connection uh assistant Dline coach,
coach uh Demetri Brown. Um he was at UCF
last year so that kind of had a little
push to it. A
>> little push to it. How was he through
the process? Did you guys talk through
uh what could be the possibility of
being here?
>> Right. Yeah. He um we talked a little
bit about it. Like he was just telling
me um Jerry Jones, he uh liked me a lot
and just and just like how the staff
there liked me a lot as well. So some
positive things.
>> Yeah, there's a lot of excitement around
what you can bring just from an
immediate standpoint, but also what you
can grow into. What are some of the
areas of your game that you feel like
are NFL ready uh right now going into
your rookie year?
>> Right. Uh getting after the quarterback,
I say just my pass rush arsenal. Um how
I'm able to just like disrupt the
quarterback, get him off his track, and
also sack him as well. So I say that.
>> And what are some of the things you feel
like can still be worked on? Still not
an unfinished product as a rookie. What
are the things that you're looking
forward to?
>> Right. I'm uh looking forward to just
being that disruptor in the uh run
defense as well. just setting a a strong
edge and just creating havoc in that run
defense just so I can get the
opportunity to rush the passer.
>> So for Cowboys fans that may not know
you quite yet behind the scenes, what do
you like to do outside of football? What
are some of your hobbies?
>> Right. Um outside of football, I like to
game. Um go to the gun range, cook a
little bit. Shoot, I'm I'm chill. So I I
don't do a lot.
>> I like Hey, gun range, you're fitting
right in at the moment. When it comes to
gaming, what are we picking up? What
what's the game,
>> right? Uh I play PC, so play a little
Arc Raiders with Marvel Rivals. And then
if I go to the Xbox 2K,
>> Madden.
>> Okay. So, you you got some some
versatility to you there, too. Not just
on the field, off the field, you've got
some versatility. I like it. Uh when did
you know that the NFL was a possibility
for you? What what point in your career
that you felt like it was an attainable
goal?
>> Right. Um, after my 2023 season, uh, I
had a a good year, breakout year, and I
was kind of in a DPR role, so I wasn't a
starter, just like kind of a third down
and then sometimes first and second, but
just seeing how I got seven and a half
sacks on like 180 pass rush snaps and
just like I said, seeing how I was able
to get to that quarterback, uh, it it's
it was like that from there.
>> No doubt. And then that from that point
forward, you continued to improve at
UCF. Why UCF? And then I think the
second question now in today's college
football landscape is why did you stay
at UCF?
>> Right. Uh why UCF is because like it was
co so during my recruiting process I
didn't have any official visits. So
everything was on Zoom. So UCF kept the
best connection and I stayed at UCF just
because I was developing into that
leadership role from the junior to
senior year and just growing into it.
And so we had younger guys in our
defensive end in room that I also wanted
to help out and show them that you can
stay at one school and still be great.
>> What does loyalty mean to you? Showing
that you were loyal to UCF for those
those four years. I mean, what does that
mean now going to the NFL?
>> Right. Loyalty means everything to me.
Like if you're not loyal, then how can
someone trust you? Like you could just
be already on one one foot out, one foot
in, and I don't like those type of guys.
So yeah, loyalty means a So, you're
already two feet planted now just after
hearing your name called a couple hours
ago. It's exciting for Cowboys fans to
hear. Who are you most excited to meet
on the Cowboy side of things?
>> Uh-huh. Shoot, everybody. Really? Shoot.
Whole D front. Like, I'm just ready to
build those bonds, relationships with my
teammates like I did at UCF. It's like
that brotherhood, that camaraderie in
the locker room. You can't beat it.
>> Have you heard from anybody yet to this
point? But yes, I heard from uh Donovan
and uh I forgot, but a few guys I've
heard from. Yeah.
>> What did Donovan say?
>> Uh he was just telling us uh I think me
and Caleb DS were in a group chat
together. He was just telling us like
good luck. If we need anything, just hit
him up. Like he's here for us and stuff
like that. Just someone like kind of
like a big brother, I'd say.
>> Just ready to step in and help the
rookies out.
>> Yeah. What was your perception of the
Cowboys from the outside looking in? You
grew up in Louisville. You you go down
to Orlando. you spend the four years
there, but
>> from afar, what have you always seen
with the Cowboys?
>> Right. Shoot. It's America's team. Like
just seeing how from um like when Deion
Sanders, like I wasn't alive, but just
seeing how when Deion Sanders played for
the Cowboys to say Demarcus Lawrence to
now, it's just like great have came
through this program. Michael Irvin, all
those Dak Prescott, he's a great right
now. So, like just seeing how the
Cowboys culture and fan base also sticks
hard and supports their team. I like
that. I love that.
>> What year were you born?
>> Uh, 2003.
>> 2003. And you're bringing up Deion
Sanders and Michael Irvin as your
Cowboys. There's a lot of Cowboys fans
right now that are excited that those
are the names you brought up to talk
about the greatness in Dallas, but
you're you're trying to add to that. Who
are some of the guys that you modeled
your game after that have already been
playing in the NFL?
>> Right. Um, Chandler Jones, Will Anderson
Jr., and um Denil Hunter. I like to
watch those guys just the way they use
their strengths. Um Chandler Jones how
he uses his length. Denil Hunter, he's
just unorthodox pass rusher. So I love
that. And then Will Anderson, he's just
relentless and he has a bag.
>> Oh, he does. The pass rush bag is deep
and you've got one of those that you're
bringing to Dallas. Exactly.
>> Last one for you. The the draft process
is so hectic and it it continues to get
hectic all the way up until that first
week. How excited are you for that
moment to be able to walk out of the
tunnel with your new teammates and then
get to play in the NFL for the first
time? What do you anticipate that moment
looking like?
>> Right. I'm really excited. I feel like
it's going to be a very intense moment.
I might have a few butterflies, but
they're going to go away, but just I
don't even know how to describe it. I
don't know how I would be feeling. It's
going to be crazy.
>> Maybe a little bit about how you felt
last night whenever you guys picked up
Malachi. Congratulations on getting to
this point. appreciate you and welcome
to Dallas.
>> Yes, sir. Appreciate you.